Guide to the Vassar College Vietnam Era Protests Collection, 1962-1972
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Vietnam Era Protests Collection
1962-1972
0.6 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of clippings, leaflets, and correspondence related to campus protests at Vassar College during the height of the Vietnam War.
Scope and Content Note
An artificial collection of clippings, leaflets, and correspondence related to campus protest at Vassar College during the height of the Vietnam War.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Digitized newspapers in the Vassar College Digital Library
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements--United States; Peace movements--United States--History--20th century; Student movements--United States--History--20th century; Students--Political activity--United States--History--20th century
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Events and Issues
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2015. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2023.
Acquisition Information
Presumably gathered by Vassar librarians from administrative offices and publications.
Additional materials were the gift of Judith Schwartz (VC 1964), 2023. [A2023-016]
Container List
- General Materials on Vassar and Vietnam, 1969-1970, undated (Folders 1.1 - 1.5)
- "Southeast Asia: An American Crisis - A Study Compiled by the Vassar Strike Research Committee,", circa 1970 May; [3 copies] (Folder 1.6)
- Materials on Strikes and Protests concerning Vietnam, 1962-1972 (Folders 1.7 - 1.11)
- Vassar College Administrative Materials on Vietnam (Folder 1.12)
- Vassar Committee to end the War in Vietnam (Folder 1.13)
- Materials Against IBM (Folder 2.1)
- V.T.T. Materials (Folder 2.2)
- Vassar and Vietnam - Newspaper Articles, 1962-1972 (Folders 2.3 - 2.11)
- Strike Daily, 1970 May (Folders 2.12 - 2.15)
- Commercial Materials on Vietnam, undated (Folder 2.16)